The boldest rescue in history
Raid on Entebbe is a drama, thriller, tv movie film directed by Irvin Kershner.
Based on a true operation by Israeli commandos.
An Air France flight is hijacked by the Popular
Front for the Liberation of Palestine.
The airplane landed in Uganda.
The terrorists released some passengers, keeping
94 Jews and 12 air crew hostage.
The Israeli government would not negotiate.
A rescue plan was devised, and less than 100 commandos were flown across Africa
to rescue the passengers in surprisingly successful operation.
Brig. Gen. Dan Shomron, played by Charles Bronson.
Yitzhak Rabin, played by Peter Finch.
President Idi Amin - Jr., played by Yaphet Kotto.
Daniel Cooper, played by Martin Balsam.
Wilfred Boese, played by Horst Buchholz.
Maj. Gen. Benny Peled, played by John Saxon.
Raid on Entebbe is a 1977 NBC television film directed by Irvin Kershner.
It is based on the Entebbe raid, an Israeli military operation to liberate
hostages at Entebbe Airport in Uganda, on July 4, 1976.
The portrayal of Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin was Peter Finch's final
performance; he died five days after the film's release.
Raid on Entebbe portrays the discussions within the Israeli government, the military
rescue of the hostages, and the controversy prompted by the rescue.
It was one of three films made in the 1970s based on the Entebbe raid, Victory at Entebbe was
rushed through production by ABC and broadcast one month earlier in December 1976.
Operation Thunderbolt (1977, Israel) was the third  A fourth film, Entebbe (titled 7
Days in Entebbe in the U.S.) was released over four decades later in 2018.
The film explores themes of israel, war on terror,
uganda, based on true story, terrorism.
The tone is emotional and intense.